Adnan Tanveer

P: +92-316-6874844 | adnantanveer066@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/adnantanveer52

Summary

Content Marketing Specialist with 4+ years of experience. Helped an affiliate website to achieve a \$5M revenue mark. Improved organic search rankings from page 3 to Top 5 for 10+ high-competition keywords for a leading eCommerce brand and increased their organic traffic by 21%. Seeking to leverage exemplary project/team managing skills, data analysis skills, and broad technical SEO knowledge as an SEO Strategist.

EXPERIENCE

Chessonics - USA

eCommerce Marketing Manager - Freelance

Jan 2023 (Ongoing)

- Develop and implement a comprehensive digital marketing strategy to increase website traffic and conversion rates.
- Utilise paid advertising campaigns on search engines to reach target customers and increase sales.
- Manage and optimise email marketing campaigns to engage with customers and increase loyalty and repeat purchases.
- Analyse website data and customer behaviour to make data-driven decisions, and continuously improve the user experience and online sales.

iSkills Multan - Pakistan

Full Stack Web Development - Internship

June 2022 - Aug 2022

- Worked on a real world project under the supervision of Sir M Tanveer Nandla.
- Managed one of their client's eCommerce websites.
- Optimised the Javascript code to make the website run smoothly.
- Made sure their core web vitals are all working fine in terms of the coding part.

VPN.com - USA

Content Marketing Specialist - Freelance

June 2022 (Ongoing)

- As their content specialist, I helped them gain more organic traffic by 10x in just 5 months only on the basis of the right content strategy and optimization
- Researched and implemented search engine optimization recommendations through Ahrefs and provided keywords with less difficulty to increase the chance of ranking by 60%.
- Led a team of 6 members and managed their work through Asana Project Management to produce content for their website.

Saddle Finance - USA

Senior Outreach Expert - Freelance

March 2022 - May 2022

- As the outreach specialist I looked after their outreach campaigns and got to increase the leads by 58%.
- Recommended changes to their content strategy and implemented them in their team which decreased their work complexity by 50%
- In charge of creating new processes and improving communication between departments to reduce the complexities of inter-departments by at least 50%

Paradise Media LLC - USA

- Conducted the daily outreach and enrollment through Paradise Media and gathered information on sponsored and guest posts.
- Increased awareness of affordable posting opportunities by facilitating weekly meetings.
- Maintained client caseload of approximately 40 new and existing cases per month and conducted weekly follow-ups to ensure correct enrollment procedure through Slack and ClickUp.

TechUp Solutions - Pakistan

Technical SEO Associate - Contract (Remote)

June 2018 - Sep 2021

- Created 20+ SEO campaigns for websites with complex media and big structures.
- Took average CTR for 20 transactional keywords from 20% to 34%.
- Prepared informational and reader-friendly reports.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Led a team of 18 members to handle the entire Content Marketing for different clients. Made an Airline Reservation JAVA Web Application on Apache Tomcat. Worked on Numpys and used Pandas for Data Visualization Scored straight A's in almost every programming course.

EDUCATION

Ghulam Ishaq Khan Institute - Topi, Pakistan

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Aug 2018 - June 2022

ADDITIONAL

Technical: JAVA, C, C++, HTML/CSS, Javascript, PHP, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Databases (mySQL); Proficient in MATLAB, Ahrefs, SEMrush, Screaming Frog, MOZ Pro, WordPress. **Non-Technical**: Search Engine Optimization [SEO], Content Marketing, Email Outreach, Keyword Research, Backlinking.

Certifications & Training: Advanced Search Engine Optimization from **iSkills**, Digital Marketing Training Certificate from **Digiskills**